[Music]
it's finally happened
i have
the last piece of the puzzle the last
belt
and i'm gonna put it right there and i
can also add it straight
to my gauntlet if you look at my right
hand
the red belt is there which means i can
do what i've been planning to do
since the very beginning i could take my
hand
and
[Music]
foreign
i have snapped all of the doors into my
shulker box and i even took some of the
weirder doors as well including the
water ones
i've got so many doors i think i got
just about every single door that i
physically could the only person who
really escaped was etho
who doesn't have any kind of door
whatsoever he has a very strange base
it's worth going and have a look at that
so we're gonna pop these doors where
nobody can get them and i think i'm
going to enjoy
having this on my hand for a while so
anyway welcome back to another episode
of hermitcraft last episode
we built this
it isn't completely 100 finished as you
can see up there but for the most part
there's been a lot done
a lot done
in fact there's actually so much done in
here that i think it's time i moved my
attention back outside because this is
so functional and i have been slowly
putting all my goods in the right chests
using this amazing sorter i mean you can
see how busy this has been
i think it's time i did bring my
attention back outside i think there's
some details missing and definitely a
bit on the side and we're not gonna look
at the back but you know what that's
like but before that i actually need to
meet up with mumbo jumbo who has seen my
signs and is going to meet me in the
shopping district for our first mumbo
for mayor meeting at the new
headquarters that we made last episode
mumbo jumbo
hello our future mayor
the future the future
that is very very confident of you that
is
i mean the pressure's definitely on i
feel like a lot of people have heard
about this mumbo for mayor thing and
yeah i i don't know what's going on mate
to be honest with you
i
i've kind of been caught a little bit
off guard i can i'll fill you in um so
i'm campaigning for you to be mayor
and
that's a thing and i've made a
headquarters for us
oh sweet so we actually have like so we
have a place uh a den like a hub where
we can conduct mayoral activities and
like perform all right okay
i thought i'd meet you here because i
wanted you to try the diamond throne on
for size see how it see how it fits
am i allowed to actually stand in it i
mean i'm not yeah there's there's no man
to tell you off is there
that's pretty true
who's going to stop me how do i look do
i suit it um
yeah you don't
yeah
you look
interesting i'm going to get down
i'll say the thing i'll say the thing i
say it's very you
i mean
my face doesn't suit these sorts of
things i can't have this sort of luxury
without with the face like
have you seen this by the way you've
seen the posters i've put up right yes
yeah yeah yeah yeah there's other people
have have copied look at this vote scar
trees and cats for all
what we don't even have promises like
that on our poster we just have a couple
of promises i've kind of promised
everyone facial hair anyway let me let
me come and show you that okay the
headquarters dude let me show you all
right quarters okay okay whereabouts
we're going uh to the right past the
concrete shops
i don't know why there's two there we go
look at this stop over here for a second
take take a look at this
[Laughter]
well it's very obvious whose sport is it
is on brand it is on brand no one's
being mistaken there this is like i i
don't even know how to describe this
this is like the worst superhero base
ever i mean that in like a positive way
i've got my own my own facial hair as as
my base how do you get into this place
oh yeah there's a little platform here
at the back that you you get and yeah
you kind of fly in there we go okay see
i was kind of expecting like splitting
waterfalls or or you know i don't know
how much budget you think i've got for
this campaign
take a seat take a seat okay okay all
right and let us start our first mayoral
campaign meeting
it is exciting it is exciting okay so
obviously you're running for me to be
mayor that's
it was unexpected okay but it clearly
the people want it because it seems sort
of it seems to have gone around it seems
to be very popular okay i'm hearing
nothing but mumbo for mayor at this
point in time which is great our mayoral
campaign is clearly onto a winner the
one question i do have for you though is
like what how does one how does one do
meryl stuff like what does the mayor do
what is the plan for our campaign but i
feel like we need to back it up with
some some good plans and strategies for
merrell stuff
you didn't see the poster you saw the
poster right yeah i mean i saw the post
but that's just advertising the merrell
campaign what that's the what do you
plan on doing the poster is the plan
mumbo for mayor right
mumbo for mayor
plan
there's the plan right there in red and
white
that can't be the plan dude no no no the
advertisement for the mayoral campaign
isn't the plan that's just telling
people that i'm running from there
that's not a plan there's no plan now i
don't know what mayors do they sit on
the diamond throne and stuff and i don't
think that's all they do they've got
other things to do green but the poster
look at the poster mumbo i mean it's a
good poster i mean if there if if ever a
poster was was the plan
it's been executed well
okay haven't really got a plan i didn't
think i'd get this far
i didn't think anything through
uh
well what is the plan then i don't know
i why am i asking you what are you sure
the post is not enough
i mean i'm starting to think that maybe
the post is enough um
well what if i was to
what if i was to build some some someone
you know i could build one build someone
yeah we could build someone to come into
the campaign
like artificial intelligence style
engineering
yeah like a redstone machine
yes a merrell bot
a green mumbo merrill bot
a grumbot
i am frequently astounded by what's
possible with redstone so i'm not even a
little bit surprised i okay so i think i
think we could definitely do that um
like an outball thing it just tells us
the answer exactly tells us exactly what
to do
exactly yeah so we we present a mayoral
question perhaps we feed it some mayoral
information so it knows what to do yeah
and then and then and then we ask it
meryl questions and it gives us meryl
answers and then maya
okay cool no i i'm down with that okay
so if i can build the outside of it
because i don't know redstone and then
you do the technical doodads on the
inside okay and then we've got a grumbot
so you will have a handsome smart
grumble you'll do the outside i'll do
the inside and then
mare i'm just going to say mer
like that's that's just what happens you
press the button on the ground and you
become men yeah congratulations
i mean before before we do that there is
something i'm gonna have to ask you to
do i know uh sitting here i've realized
that could you take your helmet off for
me just one sec yeah yeah no problem
well
i was about to say maybe actually i took
that off very hastily i probably should
have given you like a couple seconds to
warm up
that is not the face of someone people
are gonna is gonna vote for i'm just i'm
gonna put that out yeah please don't
take any offense to it i wouldn't vote
for you and i'm i'm running for you i'm
running this campaign and i would
currently would not vote you need to get
your mustache back it is right okay it
is probably your one and only best
feature do you know what i mean
right
i'm gonna
yeah okay fine
i feel like that was a slide egg
i'm gonna ignore it in the meantime
i'm gonna send you a skin to solve this
problem
okay i need you i need you to put it on
okay okay okay
much better
really i haven't looked yet what do i
could you give me like an audio
description
so you take like a paper and you pop it
on your head that's
basically what's happened
you made that sounded like you were
putting a piece of paper on your own
hair
that's really okay let me
oh my goodness i've got a handle and
everything have i got a logo on the back
of my head yeah yeah yeah turn around
lunch bag
lunch bag it feels greasy
yeah there might be a little might be a
little burger grease in there somewhere
but some spare chips
a couple of dried chips in there um and
i've drawn drawn a little mumbo face on
it i must admit yeah
way better i'd vote for okay
okay but i still should probably get my
mail
i don't care what it takes go and beg
tango if you have to buy it back i i
don't know what you got to do but your
job
is to get your mustache back from tango
we can deal with like the the thing
shaved out the back of your head because
people aren't voting for the backing
yeah
yeah yeah okay okay so so plan is okay
the plan is i guess the plan is right
now
is is acquire mustache make grumbot
yes i think we missed a few steps but
that's that sounds about right
i'll get started on that then
you look like the worst superhero i've
ever seen
be one
you know watching the sunsets from the
mustache is oddly satisfying
this is the spot it's so calming
so we now know
the plan mumbo and i don't have a plan
so we're going to make a robot that
gives us a plan
i've uh got myself some materials
for this machine
i have no idea what to do i i don't know
what
i don't know how big it needs to be i
don't know what it needs to be made out
of i don't know what it's gonna look
like so i'm just gonna guess i'm gonna
try and put the features of me and mumbo
into this machine
now the mumbo for mayor campaign has
been
very very successful
but i think it's best that the people
that are promoting mumbo for me you know
leaving comments and stuff
definitely keep it to our comments mine
and mumbos don't go spreading it around
the internet please it can be very
frustrating for other people so mumbo
for mayor keep that in our comments and
as for the other candidates please it
would be absolutely amazing if you gave
them as much support as you give us this
is a competition slash rey slash fight
for the diamond throne that's entirely
fun between all of the hermits so let's
all try and make this the most positive
experience for absolutely everyone so
just as much as you support me you
should support the others speaking of
the others i think it's finally been
revealed who else is after that thing
the diamond throne and one of them is
stress monster who has gone with the
campaign
gg get gorgeous and it says vote
gorgeous but i feel like i feel oh there
it is there is there's two versions
stress for mayor there we go and then
we've got false symmetry so stress
monster full symmetry mumbo jumbo
a boy
and we've got probably the worst
campaign
scar look at this really bright colorful
really bright colorful he's got a dark
sign
with normal text on it
vote scar trees and cat that's so
difficult to read scarlet from back here
you can't read that at all so we got
scar stress false and mumbo and joe
hills for the dog and i've actually seen
a couple more headquarters pop up
literally pop up there's a hot air
balloon
vote scare
oh this is really nice you know it's
made my little mustache look pretty
pathetic look at this
that is such a cool effect
the angle of that
very nice
and the way that he's put all of those
fences together
smashing i mean this is why we got to
support our fellow hermits right because
they're doing a better job
[Laughter]
i mean i still really like this i think
there's something very elegant and nice
about this meeting room and i'm about to
expand this but something also about
this scar
gonna be some real competition and then
over here there's another headquarters
that can only belong to false symmetry i
believe this is in the same style as her
base
and we can spy on the headquarters right
now
yep false for mare i don't know where
stresses is if she's got a headquarters
yet
but it would be cool to see what that
looks like when it pops up
it looks like it looks like the mayor
campaign is really starting to get going
so that brings us on to actually build
the grumbot machine
now
i think what i'm going to do because i i
don't know how big this machine has to
be
i'm going to make a platform
out the back here and then build the
machine on it
and then later down the line i will
build the building it goes in so i'm
working a bit backwards topsy-turvy i'm
gonna build what's inside the building
and then build the building afterwards
hopefully that makes sense let's get
into it with a new time lapse
building the grumbot
let's go
[Applause]
[Music]
behold
the grumbot
look how happy it looks this design was
a lot harder to nail down than a lot of
other things i've done in hermitcraft
this this took a really long time i
think i've got about eight different
designs
for various grumbots but this is what i
settled on it's got my fringe it's got
mumbo's mustache
and it's a robot i think that is three
boxes checked it currently doesn't work
obviously because there's nothing
technical inside now if there needs to
be more space for mumbo there is like
there's some there's some room to expand
out the back if we need to but uh i i
think mumbo can do pretty well with that
then hopefully we go like boop and then
something will come out here our
instructions will be dispensed now there
is something i really need to point out
there's this green
like the the matrix text going down the
face of the grumbot this was an idea
given to me by bdubs and oh my goodness
thank you so much b dubs what a
suggestion the banners
they sway ever so slightly in the wind
even though there's no wind in minecraft
but it gives the illusion
maybe i should uh maybe i should build
the platform a bit bigger but it gives
the illusion that there's like this
green text moving down the screen it
actually makes it look alive just
because of that very
very subtle sway
in the banners now this is the banner
here and all i've done is just laid it
over each other again and again and it's
just produced the most amazing effect
for grumbot now when you're standing
here you can just about see and you'll
also notice that it's kind of doing like
a pose and this is intentional because
grumba is basically shrugging and saying
i don't know either
so whatever you get out of it it's kind
of just imagine the granbot's going eh
this is what you do next so that is a
big job done and i'm so thankful that i
didn't build the building around this
first because i had no idea it would be
this enormous it is a huge build
it's much bigger than the headquarters
itself
but from a distance
look how cool that is hold on if i
position myself correctly can i make the
mustache like go on the grumbot
the answer is not really and the other
thing is it totally blocks my favorite
spot for the sunset
grombot's just like i know you you built
me here huh
i don't know
i'm
i am extremely pleased with this and i'm
probably going to leave this for now
because i've spent more than enough time
designing robots and doing mayoral
campaigns i have just a few things left
to do because unfortunately it is that
time look at that in the background i
have a few things left but unfortunately
it is that time again
we have run out of time oh my goodness i
just wanted to check up on the diamond
situation because i the great thing
about building
that oh wow look at them
again again my sunset gets taken away
from me the great thing about building
so close to the shopping district
if i ran out of stuff i just came over
here and i shot and i probably spent
over a stack of diamonds building that
thing not that it matters because we
have been selling
lots of goodies including things that
we're currently running out of stock i
never thought the name tag thing would
be so popular again we're not we're not
selling any dirt but anyway i'm afraid
that is it for today's episode it has
been a busy one we snapped our fingers
and we got rid of everyone's doors uh
well everyone that i i could get
and we have had a meeting with mumbo we
have a plan
and now we have
a grumbot what is a grumbot not even we
know i'll see you in the next episode
good bye
you